https://www.cority.com/privacy-shield-statement/

Solutions
Environmental ManagementOccupational Health SolutionErgonomics
- Industrial Ergonomics- Office Ergonomics
Industrial HygieneSafety ManagementQuality ManagementHospital Employee HealthOccupational Medicine
Services
Customer SupportUser CommunityProfessional Support
View all solutions >
AnalyticsBusiness IntelligenceMobile AppsSafety ComplianceTraining ManagementCority PlatformTechnical Highlights
Domain Solutions
COVID19 Return to WorkIndustry 4.0 / Digital TransformationOperational ExcellenceOperational Risk ManagementSafety CultureServicesSustainabilityWorker Well-Being
Solutions by Industry
Aerospace & Defense IndustryAutomotive IndustryChemical IndustryConstruction IndustryFood & Beverage IndustryHospitals & Medical CentersManufacturing IndustryMining & Metals IndustryOil & Gas IndustryPublic Sector IndustryPharma / Biotech / HealthcareRetail IndustryUtility Industry
View all industries >
Company
About UsAwardsMeet Our ExpertsPartners
Customer StoriesResources
News & Events
NewsEvents
By Type
BlogCustomer Success StorieseBooks & WhitepapersWebinars
By Topic
Environmental ManagementEvaluating EHSQ SoftwareIndustrial HygieneOccupational HealthSafety ManagementQuality ManagementCOVID-19 ResponseApplication Interfaces & Integrations
COVID-19
Return to Productivity SolutionRemote Work Home Office Ergonomics Pandemic Planning Technology for the Pandemic COVID-19 Webinars Partner Resources
Contact Us
Privacy Shield Statement
Privacy Shield StandardsThis Privacy Shield Privacy Statement (the “Statement”) sets forth the privacy principles followed by Medgate America Corp., a subsidiary of Cority Software Inc. (“Cority”) in connection with the transfer and protection of “Personal Information” received from the European Union (E.U.) and Switzerland.About The Privacy Shield FrameworkCority complies with the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework and the Swiss – U.S. Privacy Shield Framework as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal information transferred from the European Union and Switzerland to the United States, respectively. Cority has certified to the Department of Commerce that it adheres to the Privacy Shield Principles. If there is any conflict between the terms in this privacy policy and the Privacy Shield Principles, the Privacy Shield Principles shall govern. To learn more about the Privacy Shield program, and to view our certification, please visit https://www.privacyshield.gov/.The E.U.-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework was jointly established in 2016 by the United States Department of Commerce and the European Commission (EC) as a method for transferring Personal Information from the E.U. to companies in the United States (U.S.) in compliance with E.U. data protection law. On July 12, 2016, the European Commission ruled the Privacy Shield Framework adequate under E.U. law to govern data transfers between the E.U. and the U.S.The Privacy Shield program, overseen by the International Trade Administration (ITA) within the U.S. Department of Commerce, is a voluntary self-certification process for U.S. organizations allowing them to reap the benefits of the Framework. Companies seeking to register must make a public commitment to abide by the Privacy Shield principles. That commitment is enforceable under U.S. law.“Personal Information” means information that can directly or indirectly lead to the identification of a living person, such as an individual’s name, address, e-mail, telephone number, license number, medical identification number, photograph, or other identifying characteristic. The identification can occur by reference to one or more factors specific to the individual’s physical, physiological, mental, economic, cultural or social identity. Personal Information does not include information that has been anonymized, encoded or otherwise stripped of its identifiers, or information that is publicly available, unless combined with other non-public personal information.ScopeThis Statement governs Personal Information transferred from countries in the E.U. and Switzerland to the United States on behalf of Cority. It applies to Personal Information in electronic and off-line formats.Third PartiesCority will not share personally identifiable information with third parties unless stated at the time of collection and except as follows:Cority may store customer data with third-party data centers or managed service platforms as part of Cority’s hosted software offering, but only with third parties that meet Cority’s information security standards, as evidenced by certifications for their information security management system (ISO 27001, SAS 70).Cority’s corporate website contains links to other sites. Cority is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such third-party websites. Third party vendors, including Google, display Cority online advertisements on sites on the internet. These third-party vendors, including Google, use cookies to serve ads based on a user’s prior visits to Cority’s website. Users may opt out of Google’s use of cookies by visiting the Google advertising opt-out page. Also keep in mind that Cority’s website may make chat rooms, forums, message boards, and/or news groups available to its users. Please remember that any information that is disclosed in these areas becomes public information and you should exercise caution when deciding to disclose your personal information.Use of CookiesWhen you view one of our websites or advertisements, we may store some information on your computer. This information will be in the form of a “Cookie” or similar file and will be used to determine ways to improve our websites, advertisements, products or services. For example, Cookies allow us to tailor a website to better match your interests and preferences.Privacy Shield PrinciplesThe following privacy principles apply to the transfer, collection, use or disclosure of Personal Information from the E.U. and Switzerland by Cority.Notice: Cority informs individuals in the E.U. and Switzerland about the purposes for which it collects and uses their Personal Information, how to contact Cority, the types of third parties with which Cority shares their Personal Information, and the choice and means Cority offers for limiting the use and disclosure of their Personal Information.Choice: Cority will not process Personal Information about E.U. or Swiss individuals for purposes other than those for which the information was originally obtained or subsequently authorized by the individual unless the individual affirmatively and explicitly consents (“opt-in”) to the processing, or unless an exception applies. Cority also provides E.U. and Swiss individuals with the opportunity to withdraw consent at any time (“opt-out”), in which case their Personal Information will not be further processed.Consistent with the Privacy Shield supplemental principles, Cority may not be in a position to furnish notice in certain limited situations. Specifically, notice is not required where the processing of E.U. or Swiss Personal Information is necessary to respond to a government inquiry; is required by applicable laws, court orders or government regulations; or is necessary to protect Cority’ legal interests and providing notice would interfere with those interests.Accountability for Onward Transfers: Cority complies with the Privacy Shield Principles for all onward transfers of personal data from the EU and Switzerland, including the onward transfer liability provisions. Cority will only transfer Personal Information about E.U. and Swiss individuals to third-parties where the third-party (a) has provided satisfactory assurances to Cority that it will protect the information consistently with this Statement; or (b) is located in the E.U. or a country considered “adequate” for privacy by the EC, and therefore is required to comply with the E.U. data protection laws or substantially equivalent privacy laws depending upon where the Personal Information originated. Where Cority has knowledge that a third-party to whom it has provided E.U. or Swiss Personal Information is processing that information in a manner contrary to this Statement, Cority will take reasonable steps to prevent or stop the processing.Security: Cority takes reasonable precautions to protect E.U. and Swiss Personal Information in its possession from loss, misuse, unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration and destruction.Data Integrity and Purpose Limitation: Cority seeks to ensure that any Personal Information held about E.U. and Swiss individuals is accurate, complete, current and otherwise reliable in relation to the purposes for which the information was obtained. Cority collects Personal Information that is adequate, relevant and not excessive for the purposes for which it is to be processed. E.U. and Swiss individuals have a responsibility to assist Cority in maintaining accurate, complete and current Personal Information about them.Access and Correction: Upon written request to Cority, Cority will provide E.U. and Swiss individuals with reasonable access to their Personal Information. Cority will also take reasonable steps to allow E.U. and Swiss individuals to review their information for the purposes of correcting their information. There are certain limitations to the Access and Correction right, as set forth on the Privacy Shield website.Recourse, Enforcement, and Liability: Cority has established internal mechanisms to verify its ongoing adherence to this Statement. Cority is also subject to the investigatory and enforcement powers of the US federal government, including the Federal Trade Commission (FTC). Cority also encourages individuals covered by this Statement to raise any concerns about our processing of their Personal Information by contacting the appropriate Cority officer at the address below or by contacting their local privacy officer or Legal Department. Cority will seek to resolve any concerns. Cority commits to cooperate with the panel established by the E.U. data protection authorities (DPAs) and to comply with the advice given by the panel with regard to data transferred from the E.U and to cooperate with the Swiss Federal Data Protection and Information Commissioner (FDCIP) and to comply with the advice given by the FDCIP with regard to Swiss individual information transferred..Limitation On Scope Of Principles: Adherence to these Privacy Principles may be limited to the extent required to meet a legal, governmental, national security or public interest obligation.Complaints and Dispute Resolution: In compliance with the Privacy Shield Principles, Cority Software Inc. commits to resolve complaints about our collection or use of your personal information. It is possible for individuals to invoke binding arbitration, however we would encourage EU and Swiss individuals with inquiries or complaints regarding our Privacy Shield policy to first contact Cority Software Inc.’s Chief Privacy Officer at:cpo@cority.com1 800 276 9120 x 226Cority Software Inc. commits to cooperate with EU data protection authorities (DPAs) and the Swiss Federal Data Protection and Information Commissioner (FDPIC) and complies with the advice given by such authorities with regard to human resources data transferred from the EU and Switzerland in the context of the employment relationship.Contact Information:Cority Software Inc.c/o Cority Software Inc.250 Bloor Street East9th FloorToronto, OntarioCanada M4W 1E5attn: Chief Privacy Officer1 800 276 9120 x 226cpo@cority.com
Contact an EHSQ Expert to Schedule a Demo
Request a demo
Stay informed!
Sign up for EHSQ news and best practices. Get notified on upcoming webinars, exclusive events and industry news.
Email
Comments
Subscribe
*I agree that the Cority Software and its group of companies can contact me regarding this inquiry and to promote their products and services. I can unsubscribe at any time.
CONTACT US
+1 416-863-6800
+1 800-276-9120
info@cority.com
Office locations
Software solution
Enterprise EHSQ Software
Environmental
IQS is now part of the Cority family.
Read the press release
Request a demo
Previous
Next
Over 800 global organizations trust Cority.
